How would it be if you purchase a plan where
you get guaranteed returns, where
you also get bonus benefits and
where you also get equity based maturity
benefit plus insurance cover and
tax free returns?
Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajput. I
am the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I have been working in the corporate sector for 15 years
and today I am
presenting to you Future Perfect Plan of ICICI Pt. Life
Insurance. This is a
savings plan where you get a lot of money
in guaranteed returns.  Plus,
some of your money is invested, allowing you to
participate in the company's profits.
Where you also get bonuses.  Plus
37% of your money is invested in equity in different companies.
And there
you can
also get a big maturity amount as terminal bonus.  And
overall you can get returns of 10 to 11%.
Which can fulfill your financial planning needs of tax free maturity
with insurance cover.
Watch this video completely and if you find the video helpful
then
please like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Raj Triple FS.
In this picture you might be seeing some data
where after paying premium for 7 years, the
policy matures in the 12th year.
ICICI had launched similar products in the past.
Where there were plans with
some mix of guaranteed plans plus equity.
Where did he give what returns?
Like I
paid premium for 7 years between 2003 and 2009.  The customer had invested
₹1 lakh and when the maturity came after 12 years in 2015,
his maturity amount was ₹17,6000
which was giving him a return of 10.58%.  After
paying premium for 7 years between 2004 to 2010,
maturity is in 2016.  It resulted in a maturity of ₹15,600.  The
returns were 9.13%.
He paid the premium between 2005 and 2011
and took maturity in 2017,
so the maturity amount was ₹16,18,000 and the
return was 9.55%.  So in the same way,
if you look at the premium till 2022 and
also look at the returns from there, then the returns have been 9.87%.
So looking at the overall average returns,
you are getting returns of 9.47% in such
products where you have a combination of bonus, guarantee
and equity.
These returns are 7 per 12,
paying premium for 7 years is for a
policy term of 12 years.  This is the picture that
you will see now, if after 7 years of premium increase,
if you take maturity at 12 years, get maturity at 15 years
or get maturity at 17th year,
then how much maturity can you get
?  Let me give you a disclaimer.  So
this is an assumption data.  These returns may be higher or
lower.  There will not be much major difference
but the difference will definitely be visible
because this screen has been taken as per the past performance.
I will explain the actual benefit illustration to you further.
How much actual benefit is there in it,
illustrated.  Plus if
performance, in which companies is
investment made?
Depending on their performance, the
terminal bonus that you receive at the end
also impacts the maturity.
So, if we assume that
if the
money you are investing in equity gets
returns in the same manner as given in the past, and the remaining
money is being received as guarantee and bonus, then
how much maturity can you get overall?
For example, if you pay a premium of ₹00
for 7 years and
take maturity in the 12th year, then you can get ₹432890.  If you take
maturity on the 15th year, you will
get ₹547425 and if you take maturity on the 17th year after 7 years and
pay a premium of ₹00, you will
get ₹642500.  If you pay ₹1 lakh annually
for 7 years, you can get ₹14 lakh in the 12th year.
You can get ₹18 lakh in the 15th year
and ₹2-22 lakh in the 17th year.
On a premium of ₹1 lakh, you can
get a maturity of around ₹43 lakh in the 17th year.  Let's
see another picture.
Pay premium for 10 years.  Maturity is taken in the 15th, 17th or 20th year.
Suppose you pay a premium of ₹1 lakh
and
take maturity in the 20th year, then the maturity amount can be around ₹35,78,000.
If
you get returns after adding equity performance and bonus and everything.
If the premium payment is for 15 years
and the policy term is, say, 25 years.
Suppose if you pay a premium of ₹1 lakh, you will
pay ₹15 lakh in 15 years.  In comparison,
you can get ₹66 lakh on its maturity.
That too tax free with insurance cover.   Keep in
mind this is estimation data.  Actual
returns may be up or down.  Talking about the
eligibility criteria of this policy,
here you
also have the option of premium payment for 5 years of premium payment term.  Option to pay premium for 7
years, 10 years, 15 years and 20 years is
also given.   The
policy term here is given from 10 years to 30
years.  You
can purchase this policy with a minimum premium of Rs 300.
Talking about the entry age here, anyone from a 3-month-old
child to a person of 55 years can
purchase this policy.  You can
purchase this policy in annual, semi-annual and monthly mode.
Maturity Benefit: On
maturity, you will get Guaranteed Maturity
Benefit (GMB) which will depend on the
premium payment term, policy term and your
age plus you will also get Guaranteed Addition.  The
guaranteed addition can range from 10% to
18%.  If the premium
payment period is 5 to 7 years, then there can be a guaranteed addition of 8% to 15%
of the annual premium.  And if the premium payment period
is 10 years, 15 years or 20 years, then
you will get a guaranteed addition ranging from 10% to 18%.  So
here you will get Guaranteed Maturity Benefit plus
Accrued Guaranteed Addition plus Revisionary Bonus
plus Terminal Bonus.  Terminal
bonus can be a large amount
due to investment in equity.  So, you should
always take the policy at full maturity, only then
you will get the benefit of terminal
and equity.  If you surrender midway,
you may suffer losses.  So, if you are
taking this policy, try to
pay the full premium and run the policy till the term
so that
you can get good maturity tax free from the equity based returns that you will get on the terminal bonus.
In this plan, you will get the death benefit of Sum
Assured on Death plus Accrued Guaranteed
Benefit or 105%, whichever is
higher.  So obviously
some award will be given on death.  Sum Assured and Death
is defined as an
insurance cover of 10 times your annual premium and a guaranteed
maturity benefit.  Now let us
understand this plan through benefit illustration.
ICICI Prudential Future Perfect Plan
and participating means it will participate in the bonus.
Non-linked means this
is not even a unit linked insurance policy.
But still it will participate here for you in equity.
From where you will
also get returns equity based returns.  Plus, this
is an individual savings product.
Here I want to give information.  You are
getting guaranteed benefits as well as bonuses.
Plus equity is also coming.
Suppose you invest in equity in U policy, then
you can invest up to ₹5 lakh.  If you
invest above that amount, the returns you get become
taxable.  If you invest in mutual funds,
you are
charged long term capital gain tax up to 12.5% ​​on the profit of whatever amount you invest.
But in this policy, despite the bonus guarantee and
investment in equity,
you will still have to pay a premium of up to ₹5 lakh.  The
subsequent return will be tax free.
Customers are investing ₹1 lakh.
His age is 35 years.  He is
also getting an insurance cover of Rs 10 lakh.
He will get maturity amount of ₹13682.  In this maturity,
₹65320
will be guaranteed and ₹52,962 will be
their bonus based maturity.  Now this
bonus will be based on maturity when terminal
bonus will be added.  Terminal Bonus: This will be
based on the performance of the equity.  How will this come?   Let
me tell you.  So,
this will be the actual asset allocation of this plan, out of which
37.88% will be
invested in equity and the
returns generated on this will be given to you at the
end of maturity in the form of terminal bonus.
So if you want to avail its benefits
then you will have to run the entire policy.  In between,
if you surrender, it may
impact the maturity increase that you are going to get from the terminal bonus as per the returns of equity performance as per the equity bonus.  Therefore,
if you are taking this policy for the entire number of years, then
pay the full premium and
wait till the end of the policy, then you will see higher
returns.
Now here, if you
pay a premium of Rs 1 lakh, then Rs 37,880 will go
into your equity.
Depending on the returns you get, you will
also see terminal bonus payouts and maturity.
Here your investment of 11.69% is going into HDFC Bank LED.
Suppose
you have invested ₹100, out of ₹100, 37.88 is being
invested here.  So out of that
7.88, 11.69% is going to HDFC Bank.
6.81% will go to Reliance Industries.
B holds 5.43% in Airtel.  Then you will see Infosys,
Larson & Tubo, Axis Bank, Tata
Consultancy, India First Bank, Mahindra &
Mahindra, ITC, UTI, Bajaj Finance, State
Bank of India, you will see the top companies of India,
you can see the list of all the companies here.  A
little bit of your money is being invested in all those companies.
Even the company has started investing in the swigs and investments in them.
Like
here investment is also being made in DAB.
Look at all the different companies, here
you have started investing in SWGI LED also.  It is happening
in ITC also.  So
here you have a small percentage in so many companies
which will be invested.
Accordingly, you will see maturity.
Now here you will see
that you are paying ₹1 lakh for 7 years.
You will see maturity in the 15th year.   The
first column you will see is Guaranteed.  Where
you will see ₹65320
in the guaranteed column.  Then you will also get a table of 4%
and companies have to follow ID NC on 8% S.
Here you will
also see revisionary bonuses.  So
along with the guarantee, you will also see the bonus column here.
Plus you will see the maturity in the 19th column
which is 136282.
So here after adding guaranteed plus revisionary
bonus etc. plus
terminal bonus, as per that impact,
your maturity can be 15 lakh instead of 13 lakh, it can
come to 16 lakh in this way.   The
overall returns you can get in this policy are between 10 to 11%.
I will not
say that you will get a return of 15%
because it is going into equity.  Not only this,
but it will help you beat inflation and
you may get slightly higher returns than the normal typical traditional policies that are prevalent in today's times.  So you
can make an assumption of 10 to 11% that you will get this much
maturity in this plan and
you will also get tax free maturity on EV up to ₹5 lakh.
Plus insurance
cover is also there for you.  You will also get the facility of Plus Loan.
Now let's talk about the revisionary bonus and how the
company has given the revisionary bonus in the Future Perfect Plan.
So let us first
understand how revisionary bonus is declared.  This is
called Guaranteed Maturity Benefit or Sum Assured Maturity or Basic Sum Assured.
Plus sum as sum of all early
declared revisionary bonuses, that is,
all the revisionary bonuses declared before this will
also be added and 2.5% of it will be given by the
company just like last year.
2.5% was given in 2023 and 2.5% was given in 2022 also.
This is not 2.5% of the annual premium,
that if you are paying ₹1 lakh premium then you are
getting 2.5%.  This is your sum assured on
maturity plus 2.5% of the
revisionary bonuses declared by you earlier.
So that is a huge
amount.  So this is declared to you every year.
So this is what you get.  Plus
you are also getting guaranteed maturity benefit.
Plus terminal bonus is also available.
And because of this equity, you are also getting a little extra bonus.
Due to which you have seen more maturity
in this plan in the past.
You are given two riders in this plan.
Accidental death benefit rider is also provided.
Plus Disabilities rider is also
provided.  If you
want to increase the insurance cover in the policy, then you
can add this benefit along with riders.
You will also get tax benefits.
You have tax benefit up to ₹1.5 lakh under Income Tax Section ATC.
And the
maturity amount covered under section 1010D of Income Tax will be
tax free.  If your premium is Rs 5 lakh
or less.  Even if this
investment is going to be in equity, still if you invest up to ₹5 lakh, the
returns on it will be tax free.  You will get a loan
up to 80% of the surrender value.  RPO and
surrender benefit is available in this policy.
Free look period and grace period
are also available.  There is a free look period of 30 days
and a grace period of 30 days
and in this 5 year policy you will
also get the benefit of revival period.  So
finally if I summarize this plan then
if you are looking for a policy where
you get insurance cover, savings
and returns that at least
beat inflation.  So this
policy will be a very good combination for you.  This will be a
very good plan which you can buy if you want to
purchase it for your children's future
or for your savings.
Where the
benefits of guarantee, bonus and equity are
also available.  If you liked the video
or want to purchase a policy from me,
then you can contact me on the number given below
and if you
want to know that any other company has a similar policy,
where
how much percentage investment is going into equity,
what returns are coming there and after
comparing, you want to purchase the policy and
want to take a second opinion
before purchasing the policy, then
you can consult on the number given below.  If you liked the video, then before
leaving, like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel
Anil Rajput through Triffer FS.
Where more than 300
insurance related videos
are already available which will
help you a lot in your financial planning.  Thank you so much.  Jai
Hind.